<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xslViewer.xsl"?>
<body>
  <head>What Can You Do With XPath?</head>
  <div>
    <p>As long as you know how to navigate the XML tree, you can characterize a document by its structural XML - its elements and attributes - as well as the human-friendly content, such as text values of those elements and attributes.</p>
    <p>With XPath, you can:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>find all values used in an attribute,</li>
      <li>identify all <code>&lt;persName&gt;</code>s that appear within <code>&lt;person&gt;</code>,</li>
      <li>return only those elements that meet a certain criteria, such as <code>&lt;p&gt;</code> only if it has a value of "nope" in <code>@rend</code>.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Whereas XML schemas and documentation wikis will tell you how an element or attribute <hi>ought to be</hi> used, XPath can tell you how an element or attribute <hi>is</hi> used. It does not, however, make any judgments about the validity or correctness of its results. This makes it a useful tool for finding examples or errors, especially when used in conjunction with human judgment, XML schemas, documentation, encoding guidelines, and/or regular expressions.</p>
    <p>XPath can be used on either a document-level, or across many texts. Generally, if used on multiple documents, the XPath is run on each, one at a time. The results may be grouped by document.</p>
    <!-- xd -->
    <p>You can also define working sets within oXygen's XPath tool. Working sets can encompass multiple directories full of XML documents. To set up a working set in oXygen, first we will need to select the document icon in the XPath toolbar: <graphic target="test.png"></graphic></p>
  </div>
  
  <changelog>
    <change who="amc" when="2015-06-06">Moved oXygen instructions to their own paragraph. Might delete it, or move it to its own document.</change>
    <change who="amc" when="2015-05-18">Moved sections into different XML files.</change>
    <change who="amc" when="2015-05-06">Basic outline using HTML/TEI hybrid.</change>
  </changelog>
</body>