<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mtx:sc xmlns:mtx="http://xplorator.org/metallix" xml:id="d1e2">
  <mtx:rh xml:id="d1e4">Why Use XPath?</mtx:rh>
  <mtx:ti xml:id="d1e7">
    <mtx:cr xml:id="d1e9">As long as you know how to navigate the XML tree, you can characterize a 
      document by its structural XML - its elements and attributes - as well as 
      the human-friendly content, such as text values of those elements and 
      attributes.</mtx:cr>
    <mtx:cr xml:id="d1e12">With XPath, you can:</mtx:cr>
    <mtx:ne xml:id="d1e15">
      <mtx:mn xml:id="d1e17">find all values used in an attribute,</mtx:mn>
      <mtx:mn xml:id="d1e20">identify all <mtx:fe xml:id="d1e22">&lt;persName&gt;</mtx:fe>s that appear within 
        <mtx:fe xml:id="d1e25">&lt;person&gt;</mtx:fe>,</mtx:mn>
      <mtx:mn xml:id="d1e29">return only those elements that meet a certain criteria, such as 
        <mtx:fe xml:id="d1e31">&lt;p&gt;</mtx:fe> only if it has a value of "nope" in the
        attribute <mtx:fe xml:id="d1e34">@rend</mtx:fe>.</mtx:mn>
    </mtx:ne>
    <mtx:cr xml:id="d1e39">While XML schemas and documentation wikis will tell you how an element 
      or attribute <mtx:pd xml:id="d1e41">ought to be</mtx:pd> used, XPath can tell you how an element 
      or attribute <mtx:pd xml:id="d1e44">is</mtx:pd> used. It does not, however, make any judgments 
      about the validity or correctness of its results. This makes it a useful 
      tool for finding examples or errors, especially when used in conjunction 
      with human judgment, XML schemas, documentation, encoding guidelines, 
      and/or regular expressions.</mtx:cr>
    <mtx:cr xml:id="d1e48">XPath is also an essential prerequisite for building or reading XML 
      schemas, XSL transformations, and XQueries. In fact, XPath 2.0 was 
      designed in conjunction with XQuery 1.0, so that if you can write XPath 
      2.0, you can write basic XQueries.</mtx:cr>
    <mtx:cr xml:id="d1e52">If you work with XML, it's very likely XPath can solve some kind of 
      problem for you. It's even more likely that XPath is already being used 
      behind the scenes to make your current work easier!</mtx:cr>
  </mtx:ti>
  
  <mtx:changelog xml:id="d1e56">
    <mtx:change xml:id="d1e58" who="amc" when="2015-06-07">Some additions and edits. Deleted oXygen paragraph.</mtx:change>
    <mtx:change xml:id="d1e61" who="amc" when="2015-06-06">Moved oXygen instructions to their own paragraph. Might delete it, or move it to its own document.</mtx:change>
    <mtx:change xml:id="d1e64" who="amc" when="2015-05-18">Moved sections into different XML files.</mtx:change>
    <mtx:change xml:id="d1e67" who="amc" when="2015-05-06">Basic outline using HTML/TEI hybrid.</mtx:change>
  </mtx:changelog>
</mtx:sc>
